Guide to the Paul L. Holmer Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Writings of Holmer, Series I
  - Published Articles / Lectures
    - "Philosophical Criticism and Christology." Journal of Religion 34, no. 2: 88-100 (1 manuscript, 1 partial [?] typescript, 1 corrected typescript, 3 further typescripts, 2 journal extracts), 1954 Apr (Box 8, Folder 109)
    - "The Uses of Devotional Literature." The Journal of Bible and Religion 22, no. 2: 99-103 (2 typescripts, including author's note to self; 2 printouts; 2 journal extracts, 1 photocopy), 1954 Apr (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - "Justification and Being Human." Chicago Lutheran Seminary Record 58: 1-7. (1 manuscript, 1 corrected typescript, 3 further typescripts, 2 extracts, 1 journal offprint in The Pulpit Service of the Ministers' Research Foundation in which the article is ascribed to "Robert B. Smith, Research Fellow"), 1954 Jun (Box 9, Folder 111)
    - "Report on a Philosophy-Theology Consultation." The Christian Scholar 37: 167-69 (2 journal offprints), 1954 Jun (Box 9, Folder 112)
    - "Karl Heim and Sacrifice of the Intellect." Lutheran Quarterly 6, no. 3: 207-19 (1 manuscript, 1 typescript, 1 page of comments from journal editors, 2 journal extracts), 1954 Aug (Box 9, Folder 113)
    - "The Nature of Religious Propositions." The Review of Religion, 19, no. 3-4: 136-149 (2 journals, 3 journal offprints, 2 typescripts), 1955 Mar (Box 9, Folder 114)
    - "The Mood of Poetry and the Truth of Faith." Frontiers (Lutheran Student Association, Chicago) 6, no. 7: 20-23 (3, 1955 Apr (Box 9, Folder 115)
    - "Kierkegaard and Religious Propositions." Journal of Religion 35, no. 3: 135-46 (1 manuscript, 1 corrected typescript, 1 typescript with note attached: "submitted copy", 1 copy of journal, 2 journal extracts), 1955 Jul (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - "On Understanding Kierkegaard." Orbis Litterarum 10: 93-106. (1 manuscript, 2 successive corrected typescripts, 3 further typescripts, 3 journal extracts), 1955 Aug (Box 9, Folder 117)
    - "Stewards of Mysteries." Cross Currents 5, no. 1 (Winter 1955): 32-38 (2 draft typescripts, 2 corrected typescript, 2 mimeographs, 1 photocopy, 1 printout, 1 manuscript, 1 "table of contents" of this and other items) (Box 9, Folder 118)
    - "The Analysis of Religious Language: Some Considerations." Frankfort University, Germany, August 1955. Lecture outlines printed by University of Chicago Summer Program (1 manuscript, 2 corrected/annotated typescripts, 2 typescripts, 3 mimeographs) (Box 9, Folder 119)
    - "Language and Truth." Motive: A Magazine of the Methodist Student Movement 15, no. 8: 4-7 (1 typescript), 1955 (Box 9, Folder 120)
    - "Christianity and Culture: A Discussion." (1955-56): published by University of Minnesota, prepared for three gatherings of ministers, 1955-56, 23 pages (1 manuscript, 1 typescript), 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 121)
    - "Something About Swenson." Swedish Pioneer Historical Quarterly 7: 123-35 (1 typescript, 1 manuscript; 2 journal extracts), 1956 Oct (Box 9, Folder 122)
    - "The Meaning of Belief." Unpublished manuscript, ca. 1956-57. (2 typescripts), 1956-1957 (Box 10, Folder 123)
    - "Kierkegaard and the Sermon." Journal of Religion 37, no. 1: 1-9. (2 manuscripts, 1 corrected typescript, 1 typescript of article as book chapter, 3 journal offprints), 1957 Jan (Box 10, Folder 124)
    - "Christianity and the Truth." Lutheran Quarterly 9, no. 1: 33-41 (1 manuscript, 1 corrected typescript, 1 further typescript, 2 journal offprints), 1957 Feb (Box 10, Folder 125)
    - "On Christianity and the Passions." Covenant Quarterly 17, no. 1: 9-17 (1 manuscript, 2 typescripts, 2 printouts, 1 journal extract, 2 journals), 1957 Feb (Box 10, Folder 126)
    - "Kierkegaard and Theology." Union Seminary Quarterly Review 12, no. 3: 23-31 (1 manuscript, 6 typescripts [3 sets of 2 each], 1 printout, 2 journal offprints, 2 journals), 1957 Mar (Box 10, Folder 127)
    - "Albert Schweitzer--The Scholar." Ivory Tower (U. of Minnesota)1: 6-8 (1 long manuscript, 1 shorter manuscript, 1 page of a corrected typescript, 2 journal extracts, 2 journals), 1957 Apr (Box 10, Folder 128)
    - "A Negative Opinion: Some Reflections on the 'Check Sheet of Christian Beliefs'." Report of the Study Group on Theology Appendix: xi-xvi. Report to the North American Faith and Order Study Conference, Oberlin, Ohio, Sept. 3-10, 1957 (2 typescripts), 1957 Sep (Box 10, Folder 129)
    - "Will Herberg: Society and Faith." Minnesota Daily, Oct. 16, p. 4; Oct. 17, pp. 4-5; Oct. 18, p. 4 1957 (2 copies of part 1, 2 copies of part 3), 1957 Oct (Box 10, Folder 130)
    - "The Professor Asks Questions." The Lutheran 40, no. 7 (November 13, 1957): 20-22. Reprinted as "Can We Be Honest About the Church?," Minneapolis Star, Nov. 16, 1957 (2 manuscripts, 1 incomplete corrected typescript, 2 further typescripts), 1957 Nov (Box 10, Folder 131)
    - "Kierkegaard and Logic." Kierkegaardiana 2: 25-42 (3 corrected outlines in English, 2 further outlines in English, 2 outlines in Danish, 1 manuscript page of notes on sources, 2 corrected typescripts, 3 further typescripts, 2 odd pages of typescript, 1 set of carbons, 1 journal extract), 1957 (Box 10, Folder 132)
    - "La Naturaleza de las Proposiciones Religiosas." Revista "Universidad de San Carlos" (Guatemala) 41: 157-72 (2 journal offprints), 1957 (Box 10, Folder 133)
    - "Modern Theology Another Evasion?" Christian Century 75: 101-03. (1 typescript, 1 journal extract, 2 journals), 1958 Jan 22 (Box 11, Folder 134)
    - "Kierkegaard's Lessons for Pacifists." Fellowship 24, no. 17: 13-16 (1 manuscript, 1 typescript, 1 journal copy), 1958 Sep 1 (Box 11, Folder 135)
    - "Flucht von der ethischen Forderung?" Zeitwende: Die neue Furche 29: 829-35. (2 journal extracts, 1 copy of journal), 1958 Dec (Box 11, Folder 136)
    - "Metaphysics and Existentialism." The Hanover Forum 5. no. 1: 47-59. (1 journal offprint), 1958 Dec (Box 11, Folder 137)
    - "Objectivity and Faith." Vox (Dartmouth College) 5: 1-8. (1 typescript, 2 journal extracts, 2 journals), 1958 Dec (Box 11, Folder 138)
    - "Metaphysics and Existentialism." The Hanover Forum 5, no. 1 (Winter 1958-59): 47-59 (1 typescript, 2 printouts, 2 journal extract) (Box 11, Folder 140)
    - "Modern Learning and Moral Responsibility." Educational Forum 23, no. 1, pt. 1: 329-336 (1 manuscript, 1 typescript, 1 typescript as chapter of book, 2 journal offprints, 1 journal), 1959 Mar (Box 11, Folder 141)
    - "Some Reflections About Law and Gospel." Lutheran Quarterly 11, no. 2 (May 1959): 124-34 (1 manuscript, 2 typescripts, 2 copies of typescripts, 2 journal offprints, 1 journal extract), 1959 May (Box 11, Folder 142)
    - "Historical Research and Christianity." Encounter 20 (Summer 1959): 367-372 (1 manuscript, 1 typescript, 1 journal offprint) (Box 11, Folder 143)
    - "Preachers and Theology." Signs and Times (Yale Divinity School) 2, no. 3 (October 27, 1961): 1-10 (2 copies). (4 typescripts of text much longer than that printed; 1 journal extract) Reprinted in Pulpit 33 (June 1962): 7-9 (two journals, text differs in reprint), 1961-1962 (Box 11, Folder 144)
    - "Scientific Language and the Language of Religion." Journal for the Scientific Study of Religion 1, no. 1: 42-55 Later version printed in The Grammar of Faith. (1 manuscript, 1 corrected typescript, 2 further typescripts, 2 journal offprints), 1961 Oct (Box 11, Folder 145)
    - Reponse to "On Understanding Holmer and Theology" by Joe R. Jones. Signs and Times 2, no. 5: 11-16., 1963 Jan 28 (Box 12, Folder 146)
    - "Theology and Education: Reply to Paul M. van Buren." Religious Education 60, no. 1: 28-31. "Symposium: Christian Education: Linguistic Philosophy and Religious Education.", 1965 Jan-Feb (Box 12, Folder 147)
    - "Contra the New Theologies." Christian Century 82 (March 17, 1965): 329-332. (2 journals, 1 journal offprint, 1 manuscript, 1 note from Libby [?], notes), 1965 Mar 17 (Box 12, Folder 148)
    - "Kierkegaard as a Critic." Religion on Campus (U. of Minnesota) 1, no. 5 (Spring 1965): 4-10 (3 copies of the journal, 1 typescript, 1 manuscript, 2 copies of typescript) (Box 12, Folder 149)
    - "The Logic of Preaching." Dialog (Minneapolis) 4, no. 3 (Summer 1965): 205-213. (1 corrected typescript, 1 print out, 2 final typescripts) (Box 12, Folder 150)
    - "Language and Theology: Some Critical Notes." Harvard Theological Review 58, no. 3: 241-261 (1 journal offprint, 5 typescript copies, 1 manuscript), 1965 Jul (Box 12, Folder 151)
    - "Theology and Belief." In Essays on Kierkegaard, ed. Jerry H. Gill. 186-197. Minneapolis: Burgess, 1969 (1 typescript, 2 typescripts) Reprinted in Theology Today 22, no. 3, (October 1965): 358-371. (1 journal offprint), 1965 Oct (Box 12, Folder 152)
    - "Metaphysics and Theology: The Foundations of Theology." Lutheran Quarterly 17, no. 4: 291-315 Later version printed in The Grammar of Faith., 1965 Nov (Box 12, Folder 153)
    - "Wittgenstein and His Influence." Sussex Outlook (Sussex University) 4, no. 4: 1-10 (1 article clipping, 4 typescripts), 1965 Nov 2 (Box 12, Folder 154)
    - "Paul Tillich and the Language about God." The Journal of Religious Thought 22, no. 1 (1965-1966): 35-50 (2 journal offprints, 1 printed computer copy) (Box 12, Folder 155)
    - "Paul Tillich: Language and Meaning." The Journal of Religious Thought 22, no. 2 (1965-1966): 85-106 (2 typescript copies) (Box 12, Folder 156)
    - "Atheism and Theism: A Comment on an Academic Prejudice." Lutheran World (Geneva) 13, no. 1: 14-25 (5 manuscripts / typed drafts, 1 German translation, 3 journal offprints, 2 typescript copies), 1966 (Box 13, Folder 157)
    - "History and Understanding." Hibbert Journal 64, no. 254: 114-118. (2 article copies, 1 manuscript, 1 typescript, 5 typescript copies), 1966 (Box 13, Folder 158)
    - "Theismus und Atheismus: Gedanken zu einem akademischen Vorurteil." Lutherische Rundschau 16, no. 1: 21-37. (2 offprints), 1966 (Box 13, Folder 159)
    - "Salem Days: In Memory of Clarence A. Nelson." Covenant Companion 56, no. 13: 4-5 (1 journal), 1967 Jun 30 (Box 13, Folder 160)
    - "Evolution and Being Faithful." Christian Century 84: 1491-1494. Also in Changing Man, ed. Kyle and Philip J. Hefner Havelden. 156-69. Garden City, NY: Doubleday, 1968 (2 journals, 1 typescript copy, 1 manuscript), 1967 Nov 22 (Box 13, Folder 161)
    - Devotional writings in The New Time, pamphlet published by National Lutheran Campus Ministry, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 162)
    - "Wittgenstein and Theology." Reflection 65, no. 4: 1-4 (1 journal, 1 journal copy, 2 typescript copies), 1968 May (Box 13, Folder 163)
    - "Ecumenics and Theology." Lutheran Quarterly 21, no. 2: 154-164 (2 journal articles, 3 typescripts, 1 manuscript, 4 typescript copies), 1969 May (Box 13, Folder 164)
    - "On Criticizing the Church." Reflection 66, no. 2 (January 1969): 1-4. Reprinted in Theology Today 26, no. 3 (October 1969): 326-334 (2 journals, 1 journal copy, 2 typescripts, 1 manuscript), 1969 Jan, Oct (Box 13, Folder 165)
    - "Theology and Happiness." Reflection 67, no. 3: 3-7. (2 journals, 1 copy, 1 manuscript), 1970 Mar (Box 13, Folder 166)
    - "Crisis in Rhetoric." Parameters and Priorities in Theological Education. 7, no. 3. (Spring 1971). (4 typescripts) (Box 13, Folder 167)
    - "Indirect Communication; Something About the Sermon (With References to Kierkegaard and Wittgenstein)." Perkins Journal 24, no. 2 (Spring 1971): 14-24. (4 typescripts, 2 manuscripts) (Box 13, Folder 168)
    - "On Being Steadfast: Jesus Christ the Same." Reflection 71, no. 1 (November 1973): 8-11 (5 different typescripts, 1 manuscript), 1973 Nov (Box 14, Folder 169)
    - "Something about What Makes It Funny." Soundings 57, no. 2 (Summer 1974): 157-74. (1 offprint of article, 4 typescripts, 1 manuscript). (Box 14, Folder 170)
    - "Religion Needs Emotion." The Lutheran 12, no. 18: 7. (1 copy of journal), 1974 Oct 16 (Box 14, Folder 171)
    - "The Minister, A Reconsideration: Meditatio, Oratio, Tentatio." Reflection 72, no. 3: 3-9. (2 journals, 3 typescripts, 1 manuscript), 1975 Mar (Box 14, Folder 172)
    - "About Liturgy and Its Logic." Worship 50: 18-28. (1 manuscript, 4 copies of typescripts [one with edits])., 1976 Jan (Box 14, Folder 173)
    - "About Black Theology." Lutheran Quarterly 28, no. 3: 231-39. (6 typescripts, 1 manuscript, 1 issue of YDS Reflection re: Black Theology with many of Holmer's notes in margins), 1976 Aug (Box 14, Folder 174)
    - "Theology, Theological Education, and Seminaries: A Reconsideration of Their Roles in the L.C.A." L.C.A. Occasional Papers, No. 1: 1-7. (2 journals, 1 journal copy, 2 typescripts, 1 manuscript, 3 separate committee reports [background?] on the L.C.A. and theological education), 1976 Oct (Box 14, Folder 175)
    - "What Theology Is and Does." Reflection 74, no. 3: 6-8. (3 copies of typescripts, 2 with edits)., 1977 Mar (Box 14, Folder 176)
    - "Making Sense Christianly: Baccalaureate Sermon [II Tim. 4:1-8]." Princeton Seminary Bulletin ns 1 (1977): 119-127. (1 manuscript, 1 typescript, 1 copy of typescript, 1 computer printout) (Box 15, Folder 177)
    - "About Pleasure and Happiness." In Wooster Alumni Magazine, 93, No. 3, Wooster, OH. (2 journals, 1 manuscript, 3 copies of typescripts), 1979 Apr (Box 15, Folder 178)
    - "Wittgenstein: 'Saying' and 'Showing'." Neue Zeitschrift fur systematische Theologie und Religionsphilosophie 22, no. 3: 222-35 (3 copies of typescripts), 1980 (Box 15, Folder 179)
    - "A Fragment of Thought about Feminism, Language and Church." Reflection 82, no. 2: 14-16. (5 typescript copies, 2 computer printouts, 1 manuscript, 1 journal), 1985 Jan (Box 15, Folder 180)
    - "C.S. Lewis: The Rules of the Game." Journal of Faith and Thought (First Baptist, Montclair, NJ) 3 (Spring 1985): 11-21, 10 (1 typescript, 1 typescript copy, 2 computer printouts [one in large print], 1 journal) (Box 15, Folder 181)
    - "On Believing in Heaven." In Pietisten 5.1 (Spring 1990): 1-4 (1 journal, 2 computer printouts, 1 manuscript). [See also "Traditional Advent Themes: (1) Heaven" and "About Heaven."] (Box 15, Folder 183)
  - Unpublished essays / lectures
    - "Bultmann and the Preacher." Unpublished manuscript (1 manuscript, 1 typescript headed "First Draft not corrected", 1 further typescript (corrected), 2 copies of separate "Bibliography Concerning Rudolf Bultmann and Demythologizing", 1955 (Box 15, Folder 184)
    - "Kierkegaard and Logical Theory." American Philosophical Association, Western Division (1955): Unpublished manuscript (2 typescripts) (Box 15, Folder 185)
    - "Faith and Learning." (1958?): Unpublished manuscript. (1 index card and 14 pages of notes [possibly unrelated?], 1 manuscript, 2 typescripts) (Box 15, Folder 185)
    - "Language, Philosophy, and Christian Faith: Unpublished manuscript (1 manuscript); "Is Supernaturalism Necessary?"; "The Persistent Question"; "Some Theological Considerations--Urban Society: Twentieth Century Predicament.", 1960s (Box 15, Folder 186)
    - "Remarks on the Occasion of a Baptism." (n.d.): Stewart bibliography: (5 typescripts), 1970s (Box 15, Folder 187)
    - "Remarks on the Occasion of a Marriage." (n.d.): 1-8. Unpublished ms. (4 typescripts), 1970s (Box 15, Folder 188)
    - "On Worshipping God: A Meditation on Psalm 73." 1-15. (5 typescripts)., ca. 1970s (Box 15, Folder 189)
    - "About Attitudes." Lecture given on October 27, 1971. (4 typescripts) (Box 16, Folder 190)
    - "About Religious Consciousness." Abstract of essay delivered at APA. 1971. (5 typescripts, 1 manuscript, article by Michael S. Bruner: "Summary of Prof. Holmer's thesis," letter from Holmer to Prof. Pasch) (Box 16, Folder 191)
    - "O Lord, Our God, Shepherd of the Fallen and Friend of Sinners." (Dec. 11, 1973): 1-2 (1 typescript; Other prayers: May 19, 1974 baccalaureate prayer, Dec. 1972 prayer; Lectures: "General Characterization of Religion"), 1972-1974 (Box 16, Folder 192)
    - "Theology and Emotions." Unpublished manuscript. (1 manuscript, 2 typescripts), 1973 (Box 16, Folder 193)
    - "About Emotions and Passions." Unpublished manuscript. (1 typescript), ca. 1973 (Box 16, Folder 194)
    - Emotions: "Introduction: Some General Conceptual Issues", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 194)
    - "The Human Heart--The Logic of a Metaphor." 1-34. Unpublished manuscript. (1 manuscript, 1 edited typescript, 2 clean typescripts), ca.1973 (Box 16, Folder 195)
    - "Prayer - Baccalaureate Service." (May 19, 1974): 1-3. Unpublished prayers. (1 typescript) (December 1972): 1. Unpublished prayer. (1 typescript), 1974 May (Box 16, Folder 196)
    - "Lewis and the Imagination." 1-22. Unpublished lecture. (2 typescripts, 2 pamphlets, 1 manuscript, 2 biographical reports on Lewis), ca. 1974 (Box 16, Folder 197)
    - "C.S. Lewis: The Logic of His Faith and Thought", no date (Box 16, Folder 197a)
      Scope and Contents
      handwritten, bound volume
    - "Two Kinds of Learning." (1974-75): Unpublished manuscript. (1 set of 3 typescripts, 2 sets of 2 typescripts), 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 198)
    - "About Happiness and the Concept, 'Happiness'.": 1-13 Unpublished manuscript. (1 journal, 2 typescripts), ca. 1975 (Box 16, Folder 199)
    - "The Case for the Virtues." 1-30. Unpublished manuscript. (3 typescripts, 2 typescripts with edits, 1 manuscript, correspondance and response), c. 1976 (Box 16, Folder 200, 200a)
    - "Traditional Advent Themes: (1) Heaven." (Nov. 29, 1977) (2 computer printouts, 2 copies of typescripts, chapel bulletin [See also "On Believing in Heaven," "About Heaven."], 1977 Nov (Box 17, Folder 201)
    - "On Receiving Mercy: A Sermon Preached at Yale University's Battell Chapel, on Palm Sunday, 1977.": 1-9 (2 computer printouts, 3 typescripts) (Box 17, Folder 202)
    - "About Understanding." Unpublished Manuscript (4 typescripts, 2 copies of typescrips, 1 manuscript, 1 copy of Signs and Times of the Yale Divinity School that includes Holmer's response to Joe R. Jones's essay "On Understanding Holmer and Theology"), ca. 1977 (Box 17, Folder 203, 203a)
    - "About Understanding and Religious Belief." Unpublished manuscript. (1 manuscript, 5 typescripts), ca. 1977 (Box 17, Folder 204)
    - "Saying and Showing: A Religious Consideration." Unpublished manuscript (1 manuscript, 1 typescript, 3 copies of typescript), 1980 (Box 17, Folder 206)
    - "Spirituality and Self-Deception." 1-13. Unpublished manuscript (1 computer printout, 4 copies of typescripts, 1 manuscript), 1980 (Box 17, Folder 207)
    - "Ministry and the World." Unpublished manuscript,(2 typescript copies), ca. 1981-1982 (Box 17, Folder 208)
    - "About Fearing God." Unpublished manuscript. (1 computer printout copy), 1984 (Box 18, Folder 209)
    - "The Transforming Power of Other-Worldliness." Sermon preached at Plymouth Congregational Church (Minneapolis, MN) 1-6. (3 copies of typescripts), 1985 Jun (Box 18, Folder 210)
    - "Necessity Laid Upon Me." Unpublished manuscript,. (6 typescript copies), ca. 1980s (Box 18, Folder 212)
    - "On Speaking the Truth in Love: Remarks on the Occasion of an Ordination." Unpublished manuscript (3 typescripts, 2 computer printouts, 2 copies of typescripts), ca. 1980s (Box 18, Folder 213)
    - "The Surpassing Worth..." Unpublished manuscript. (4 typescript copies), ca. 1980s (Box 18, Folder 214)
    - "Taught by God." Unpublished manuscript (1 computer printout, 2 typescript copies), ca. 1980s (Box 18, Folder 215)
    - "About Consciousness and Psychology." Unpublished manuscript. (1 corrected typescript, 5 other typescripts) (Box 18, Folder 216)
    - "About Heaven." (n.d.): 1-14. (1 copy of typescript, 1 manuscript). [See also "Traditional Advent Themes: (1) Heaven" and "On Believing in Heaven."] (Box 18, Folder 217)
    - "About Linguisticality and Being Able to Talk." Unpublished manuscript. (3 copies of typescript, 1 computer printout, 1 corrected typescript) (Box 18, Folder 218)
    - "About Philosophy for Everybody." 1-5. (11 typescripts, 1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 219)
    - "About Raymond Morris." 1-2. (5 typescripts, 1 manuscript) (Box 18, Folder 220)
    - "About Religion and Science." 1-13. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript) (Box 18, Folder 221)
    - "About Thankfulness." 1-8. ( 9 typescripts, 1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 222)
    - "About Theology and Concepts." Unpublished manuscript: 1-35. (1 manuscript) (Box 19, Folder 223)
    - "About the Lack of Community." 1-9. (2 typescripts, 1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 224)
    - "The Academic Game and its Logic." 1-21 (2 computer printouts [one large print], 1 typescript copy, 1 typescript, 1 manuscript) (Box 19, Folder 225)
    - "An Advent Sermon: The Gospel According to Luke." 1-7. (1 typescripts, 2 copies of typescript, 1 manuscript)., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 226)
    - "Albert Schweitzer: Thoughts and Action." 1-35. (4 typescripts) (Box 19, Folder 227)
    - "Antecedents and Motivations of Behaviorism." 1-16. (1 typescript) (Box 19, Folder 228)
    - "Axel Hagerstrom (1884-1939)." 1-3. (1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 229)
    - "Baron Friedrich von Hugel (1852-1925)." 1-4. (1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 230)
    - "The Bible and the Word of God in Contemporary Lutheranism." 1-39 (1 typescript) (Box 19, Folder 231)
    - "Breve og Aktstykker Vedronrende Soren Kirkegaard."1-3. (1 typescript). (Box 19, Folder 232)
    - "By Prof. Dr. Ed. Schweizer." 1-10. (3 typescripts), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 233)
    - "C.J. Bostrom and His Philosophy." 1-24 (1 copy) (Box 19, Folder 234)
    - "Changing Concept of the Self/the Person." (1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 235)
    - "Christianity and College." 1-9 (2 typescripts) (Box 19, Folder 236)
    - "The Church and the Intellectual Life." 1-9 (2 typescripts) (Box 19, Folder 237)
    - "Contemporary Philosophy and Religion." 1-42 (1 manuscript; also 1 manuscript of "Recent Philosophic Criticism and Supernaturalism") (Box 19, Folder 239)
    - "Creation Science and Faith." 1-8 (1 typescript, 1 manuscript) (Box 19, Folder 240)
    - "C.S. Lewis (1898-1963)." 1-3 (1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 241)
    - "The Death of Ivan Ivanovich." 1-52 (1 typescript), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 242)
    - "Decisions of Principle." 1-17 (1 typescript), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 243)
    - "Durkheim and Wittgenstein: Some Logical Questions [about] the Notion of 'Forms of Life'." 1-16 (1 typescript) (Box 20, Folder 244)
    - "Education For What?" (1 manuscript, notes), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 245)
    - "Education of Ministers." 1-29 (1 typescript), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 246)
    - "Epistemological Considerations and Evangelicalism." 1-19 (4 copies of typescripts, 1 manuscript) (Box 20, Folder 247)
    - "Esthetic Consciousness." 1-9 (2 manuscripts, 3 typescripts), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 248)
    - "The Fool says in His Heart." 1-7 (3 copies of typescripts), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 249)
    - "Gospel and Law Re-examined." 1-16 (1 typescript, 1 manuscript) (Box 20, Folder 250)
    - "Gustav Aulen and Some Remarks About 'Symbols'" (2 manuscript/typescript combos, 2 copies of typescript, 1 computer printout) (Box 20, Folder 251)
    - "Herbert Feigl." 1-4 (1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 252)
    - "How Spiritual is the Church?" 1-13 (3 typescripts, 1 copy of typescript, 1 computer printout, 1 manuscript)., n.d. (Box 20, Folder 253)
    - "If Christ Came to the University." 1-3 (1 manuscript, 1 page of typescript), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 254)
    - "Indirect Communication: Some Philosophical Issues (With Reference to Kierkegaard and Wittgenstein)." 1-13 (4 copies of typescripts) (Box 20, Folder 255)
    - "Intellectual Problems About Theological Education" 1-24 (1 manuscript)., n.d. (Box 20, Folder 256)
    - "Interpreting the Bible." 1-38 (1 manuscript, photocopies of relevant articles in ABD and Barth's Church Dogmatics ) (Box 20, Folder 257)